Guide to the Cherríe Moraga Papers, 1970-1996
Department of Special Collections
- Series XII. Electronic Media
  - Subseries a. Audiocassettes
    - NYWAR Workshop: Racism and Anti-Semitism - Bulkin, Gomez, Oliveira 1984 June (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - Outwrite '91 - readings, Moraga, et. al. n.d. (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - The Shadow of a Man - INTAR [1985?] Apr. 23 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - A Shadow of a Man - C. Moraga Performance & Critique. at The Foot of the Mountain 1986 Winter (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - Sonoma State Reading - B.& C. 1981 Nov. 13 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - "Specific Passions" - Seattle [1 of 2] 1991 Aug. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - "Specific Passions" - Seattle [2 of 2] 1991 Aug. (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - UCB Interview - "Coatlique's Call" / "Shadow of a Man" n.d. (Box 1, Folder 36)
    - Women of Color Critics Panel - UC Irvine 1986 April (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - Women of Color Teatro - KPFA 1986 Oct. 19 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - Watsonville Interview: Luisa Medina [1 of 2] 1994 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 39)
    - Watsonville Interview: Luisa Medina [2 of 2] 1994 June 29 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - Watsonville Interview: Frank Bardacke 1994 Aug. 9 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Watsonville Interview: Gloria Betancourt 1994 Sept. 5 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - Watsonville Interview: Ricardo Carvajal 1994 Sept. 6 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - Watsonville Interview: Esperanza Contreras 1994 Sept. 5 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - Watsonville Interview: Eileen Donnely, Rosie Chavez / Earthquake [English] / (a) Eileen / Rosie Chavez (Earthquake) / (b) Rosie (cont.) (5 min.) n. d. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Watsonville Interview: Barbara Garcia / (a) Interview with Barbara Garcia / (b) Interview with Barbara Garcia 1994 Mar. 31 -May 19 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Watsonville Interview: Interview with Barbara Garcia / (a) Interview with Barbara Garcia / (b) Blank 1994 May 19 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Watsonville Interview: Cruz Gomez / English with some Spanish interjected / (a) Cruz Gomez / (b) Cruz Gomez 1994 June 16 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Watsonville Interview: Reyna Guzman / (a) Reyna Guzman / (b) Reyna Guzman 1994 Aug. 27 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Watsonville Interview: Lydia Lerma / (a) Lydia Lerma / (b) Lydia Lerma 1994 Aug. 9 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Watsonville Interview: Father Michael Miller / (a) Father Mike / (b) Blank 1994 Aug. 16 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Watsonville Interview: Chavelo Moreno / English / (a) Chavelo Moreno / (b) Chavelo Moreno n. d. (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Watsonville Interview: Guillermina Rodriguez / (a) Guillermina Rodriguez / (b) Guillermina Rodriguez 1994 Aug. 29 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Watsonville Interview: Guillermina & Ricardo Rodriguez / (a) Guillermina & Ricardo [Earthquake] / (b) Guillermina & Ricardo [Earthquake] n. d. (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Watsonville Reading, # 1 / (a) # 1 Watsonville / (b) Blank 1995 Nov. 28 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Watsonville Reading, # 2 / (a) # 2 Watsonville / (b) Blank 1995 Nov. 28 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Watsonville: Excerpts from Watsonville On Strike" Video / This tape contains excerpts from a video: songs, parts of speeches, interviews, etc. [English & Spanish] / (a) Excerpts from "Watsonville On Strike" Video / (b) n. d. (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Watson: John's Compositions / (a) Watson - John's Compositions / (b) Blank n. d. (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Music for Watson Screp Reading; Tape A: Watsonville Suite; J. Santus / (1) African Female Voices; (2) Abstract Dream; (3) Latin for Ballad; (4) Maríachi / (a) Watsonville Suite / (b) Blank 1995 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Music for Watson Screp Reading; Tape B: "La Justicia" - Picket Line; "Somber Strike"; Musica Indigena Marimba / (a) (1) "La Justicia" - Picket Line; (2) "Somber Strike"; (3) Musica Indigena Marimba / (b) Jarana (instr.) G. I. 1995 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Music for Watson Screp Reading; Tape C: "Mexico es la luna" (guitar interlude); "After the Earthquake" / (a) (1) "Mexico es la luna" (guitar interlude); (2) "After the Earthquake" / (b) Blank n. d. (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Music for Watson Screp Reading; Tape D: "Standard Cumbia"; "Dolores' Song of Foreboding"; "Maríachi"; "Sonora's the Me"; "I Am Going Back" n. d. (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - In Celebration of Women Writers: Isabel Allende, June Jordan, Herriet Goldhor Lerner & Holly Near 1990 Dec. 2 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Liliana Felipe: Materia de Pescado; Con La Danzonera Dimas / (a) (1) Isela Vega o la filosofia zen; (2) Ropa Interior; (3) Los sexos de Miller; (4) Es Elena Poniatowska / (b) (5) La cumbia del pescado; (6) La cumbia del diablo; (7) Ninon o que maravilla la Sevilla; (8) San Miguel Arcangel 1989 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Eloise Klein Healy; Some from Ten Poems (1975 - 1985) 1985 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Geography Essay by Barry Lopez; Stonewall / (a) Geography by Barry Lopez / (b) Stonewall n. d. (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Starburst / (1) Rock & Roll Group; (2) Rock & Roll Star; (3) Sunshine Pack [stereo] 1985 Jan. 8 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Teatro Compesino; El Louie; Richard Campos n. d. (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Subseries b. Videocassettes
    - Cherríe's Finals: Bracho, Robles, Haro, Flanagan, etc. Theatre Performance, U.C. Berkeley; video: Ana Bartha. 1990 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      1 videocassette: sd., col., VHS
    - Chicano studies 49 Poetry reading (12.6.90) Moraga, Instructor, U.C. Berk[eley]. 1990 Dec. 6 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Circle in the dirt: dramatic reading 7/24/95. 1995 July 24 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Coatlicue's Call: Guadalupe Garcia / 1298 Haight / SF CA. 1991 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      1 videocassette (5min.): sd., col., VHS
    - DramaDIVAS: Writing class "personal ads" Kissing Bandido / Part of talk line Yvette B. Joseph 11-7-94. 1994 Nov. 7 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - DramaDIVAS: OSA Videos: "Mi madrina always danced with women." 1994 June (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - DramaDIVAS: "The Life of a DIVA." June 29, 1995 Performance. 1995 June 29 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - East Palo Alto Project: Cherríe & Oyamo Readings EPAP Plays in Progress. n.d. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - East Palo Alto Project: Dancing on the Brink. n.d. (Box 3, Folder 9)
      1 videocassette (67 min.): sd., col., VHS
    - East Palo Alto Project: Circle in the Dirt. n.d. (Box 3, Folder 10)
      1 videocassette (68 min.): sd., col., VHS
    - Giving up the ghost: Teatro by Cherríe Moraga, Directed by Leilani T. J. Miller (Original 1986 version of play). 1992 Apr. (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Giving up the ghost: Theatre Rhinoceros. Cherríe Moraga, video: Ana Bertha Camea. n.d. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Heroes & Saints: Inside City Limits show. n.d. (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Hispanic Culture Speakers Series: Pat Mora, 6-17-92; Alberto Rios 6-24-92; Lionel Garcia, 7-1-92; Cherríe Moraga 7-15-92. 1992 June -July (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Modern Times Bookstore, San Francisco: Cherríe Moraga Reading. 1993 Oct (Box 4, Folder 3)
      1 videocassette (c. 60 min): sd., col., VHS
    - Oberlin College: reading 3-21-89. 1989 Mar. 21 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - ¡ Oye Familia!: A dialogue with society (work-in-progress excerpts). A film by Jonathan Robinson, poetry and performance by Piri Thomas. n.d. (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Popol Vuh Project: Mettawee (Upstate New York tour of workshop production), Metawee River Co. 1993 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Popol Vuh Project: Public Theatre, Ralph Lee. 1994 Sept. (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Shadow of a man: ACT performance. n.d. (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Watsonville: reading at Brava studio, 05/01/95. 1995 May 1 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Watsonville: video sit-down reading, 5/1/95. 1995 May 1 (Box 4, Folder 10)
      1 videocassette: sd., col., Hi8
  - Subseries c. Computer disks
    - Chicano Studies: Creative writing, Teatro, etc. [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 1)
      I computer disk: double sided, high density [?]; 5 1/4 in.
    - Español: Lectures, epercicios, poemas, traduciones, etc. Mexico [verso: "No sirve"] [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] 1991 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      I computer disk: double sided, double density; 5 1/4 in.
    - Essays Chicana Lit., Artists Stmt., On Gug. / Ch. LTSB. / Sexual. Reviews, Self-portrait / Women's Studies [verso: Essays: UCSC "Entre Nosotras" CAC Stmt., Excerpts al La Jornada, Outwrite, Women of Aztlán] [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 3)
      I computer disk: single sided, double density; 5 1/4 in.
    - Heroes and Saints (Copy): Brava Production Version sent to WEP [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - 1. Ma Saucedo, un tributo / 2. La Prieta, Anzaldúa / 3. Castillo, poems [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 5)
      I computer disk: single sided, double density [?]; 5 1/4 in.
    - Mexican Medea: initial work [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] 1991 Summer (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - The Moraga Papers [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Organizing La Red [verso: La Red, Budgets, Grants, Pol. Act (corresp.), Contacts] [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Esta Puente Mi Espalda: Puente [verso: Puente, Promo, Promo-corresp.] [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Esta Puente Mi Espalda: backup for Puente, intro, part I, part II [1 of 2] [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] 1988 Apr. 15 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Esta Puente Mi Espalda: backup for Puente, part III, contents [2 of 2] [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] 1988 Apr. 15 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Esta Puente Mi Espalda: 1. Nellie Wong 2. Audre Lorde / Master's Tools 3. Nellie Wong under "Puente" / also poem 4. Chrystos [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Esta Puente Mi Espalda: 1. Combahee River Collective 2. Merle Woo 3. Gloría Anzaldúa "Lengua" [marked on sleeve: "copy for Dan"] [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Esta Puente Mi Espalda: 1. N. Alarcón 2. Cameron, Parker & B. Smith, prefocio 3. Littlebear, A. Valerio, R. Morales, Moraga poem; K. Ruskin, J. Carrillo, A. Morales (all under "Puente2") [verso :1. Cheryle Clark 2. Mitsuye Yamada 3. section introductions 4. Watsonville interviews 5. contenido, con apuntes de lus traductores y biografiás 6. E. Granodos 7. Ed.--general introd.] [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 14)
      I computer disk: double sided, double density [?]; 5 1/4 in.
    - Quincentenario essay and others to be published [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Shadow of a Man: Act 1 [verso: Shadow of a Man: Act 2] [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Shadow of a Man (Act version 5/1/89) version sent to NEA & New World Theatre 6/30/89 [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] 1989 May 1 -June 30 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Shadow of a Man: Shadow act one (pre-Fornes) [verso: Shadow act one] [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] 1990 Mar. (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Shadow of a Man: Sombra act one (Final version) sent to WEP, Eureka / Brava, Chicago [verso: Sombra act two] [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Shadow of a Man: Sombra copy act one [verso: Sombra copy act two] [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] 1990 Aug. (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Theatre excerpts: mother monol., daughter monol., excerpts from HEAD [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] n.d. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Theatreworks: contracts, LATA, mailing lists / family / 90 personal corresp. [verso: contracts / SEP, acting, theatre wkshp., 92 submission teatro] [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] [1990 -1992?] (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Writing workshop: misc. corresp., Third woman / contracts, grants 1987-1988, submissions / taxes-rent, gigs [verso: vitae / bio, recommendation, jobs, theatre, Mexico] [This disk is currently unavailable to researchers, pending conservation] 1987 -1988 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Circle in the Dirt: scripts [note: paper copies of files from this disk are available in series II: Manuscripts] 1995 (Box 6, Folder 1)
      I computer disk: high density, Macintosh formatted, 1.40 MB; 3 1/2 in.
    - Circle in the Dirt (EPA Project): Interviews [note: paper copies of files from this disk are available in series II: Manuscripts] n.d. (Box 6, Folder 2)
      I computer disk: high density, IBM-formatted; 3 1/2 in.
    - Circle in the Dirt: Play-in-Progress, readings, actors, scene notes [note: paper copies of files from this disk are available in series II: Manuscripts] 1995 Winter -Spring (Box 6, Folder 3)
      I computer disk: high density, Macintosh-formatted, 1.40 MB; 3 1/2 in.
    - Circle in the Dirt: East Palo Alto Project (includes a copy of Irene's work on the project) (copy of Moraga's work, too) [note: paper copies of files from this disk are available in series II: Manuscripts] n.d. (Box 6, Folder 4)
      I computer disk: double sided, double density, 1.0 MB; 3 1/2 in.
    - Circle in the Dirt: Stanford 1995, EPA interview transcripts: Chavela Rivera & Daniela Gomez [note: paper copies of files from this disk are available in series II: Manuscripts] 1995 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Popol Vuh (NY Work) (version 1-6) [note: paper copies of files from this disk are available in series II: Manuscripts] n.d. (Box 6, Folder 6)
      I computer disk: double sided, double density, Macintosh-formatted, 1.0 MB; 3 1/2 in.
    - The Popol Vuh: "Heart of the Earth" (version 7 to final) [note: paper copies of files from this disk are available in series II: Manuscripts] n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Watsonville: interviews [note: paper copies of files from this disk are available in series II: Manuscripts] n.d. (Box 6, Folder 8)
      I computer disk: high density, Macintosh-formatted; 3 1/2 in.
    - Watsonville: The LANGUAGE Bank 1. Cruz Gomez (Cruz.doc), 2. Eileen Donnely & Rosie Chavez (E & Rosie.doc) [note: paper copies of files from this disk are available in series II: Manuscripts] n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
      I computer disk: high density [?], P.C.-formatted; 3 1/2 in.
    - Watsonville: Luisa Medina interview transcription (Irene's work) [note: paper copies of files from this disk are available in series II: Manuscripts] n.d. (Box 6, Folder 10)
      I computer disk: double sided, high density, Macintosh-formatted; 3 1/2 in.
    - Watsonville: Guillermina & Ricardo, Gloria Betancourt, Ricardo Carvajal, Liliana [note: paper copies of files from this disk are available in series II: Manuscripts] n.d. (Box 6, Folder 11)
      I computer disk: high density, P.C.-formatted; 3 1/2 in.
    - Watsonville: Esperanza Contreras interview, tape transcript wordPerfect 5.1 [note: paper copies of files from this disk are available in series II: Manuscripts] n.d. (Box 7, Folder 1)
      I computer disk: double density, P.C.-formatted; 3 1/2 in.
    - Watsonville: transcripts, Barbara García on Y's Mac [note: this disk is unformatted. No other information is available] n.d. (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Watsonville: The Language bank. Transcripts - 3 tapes, David Sweet [note: paper copies of files from this disk are available in series II: Manuscripts] n.d. (Box 7, Folder 3)
- Series XIII. Essays and Reviews
  - Acosta, Belinda. "Moraga taps into the Chicana lifeline," Austin American-Statesman (1992 Oct. 24): 16 1992 Oct. 24 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Adams, Barbara. "Escaping the roles of Virgin / Mother / Whore," Ithaca Times.--Vol. 4, no. 27 (1982 Feb. 4) 1982 Feb. 4 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alarcón, Norma. Introduction to Cherríe Moraga n.d. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Alarcón, Norma. "Making Familia from scratch: split subjectivities in the work of H. M. Viramontes and Cherríe Moraga" n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Alarcón, Norma. "Making Familia from scratch: split subjectivities in the work of Helena María Viramontes and Cherríe Moraga," The Americas Review.--Vol. 15, nos. 3 - 4 (1987): 147 - 159 1987 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Alarcón, Norma. "The theoretical subject(s) of This Bridge Called My Back and Anglo-American Feminism" c. 1989 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Almaguer, Tomás. "Chicano men: a cartography of homosexual identity and behavior," Differences.--Vol. 3, no. 2 (1991) 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Azar, Diane. Untitled [on Shadow of a man] c. 1989 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Barnes, Noreen C. Untitled [on Shadow of a man] c. 1991 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bauermeister, Erica, et al. reviews of "The Bridge Called My Back" and "Loving in the War Years," 500 Great Books by Women: a Reader's Guide. n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Brinson-Pineda, Barbara. "'Onde estas Grandma': Chicana Writers and the Rejection of Silence," Intercambios Femeniles.--Vol. 2, no. 2 (1984 Spring - Summer) 1984 Spring -Summer (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Campbell, Federico. "La literatura chicana femenina en busca de una estetica propia mas alta de la denuncia" 1988 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Campbell, Federico. "Las sisters," Doble Jornada (1988 July 11) 1988 July 11 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Clark, Jil. "A book about difference..." Gay Community News (1981 June 27) [2 copies] 1981 June 27 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Cofer, Judith Ortiz. "Mujeres en lucha," Women's Review of Books.--Vol. 1, no. 10 (1984 July): 5 - 6 1984 July (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Conner, Randolph. "At the crossroads: writing in the left-handed world" 1980 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - De la Peña, Terri. "Both a Chicana and a Lesbian writer..." Off our backs.--Vol. 24, no. 6 (1994 June): 10 - 11 1994 June (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Dong, Stella. "Kitchen Table: Publishing for Third World Women," Small Press.--Vol. 2, no. 3 (1985 Jan. - Feb.): 26 - 31 1985 Jan. -Feb. (Box 1, Folder 18)
    offprint
  - Frischmann Carril, Donald. "Ecos del Pop Wuj: Desde Honduras Hasta Nueva York" 1995 Sept. 28 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    TMs, 26 pp.; TLS
  - Herrera-Sobek, María. "The politics of rape: sexual transgression in Chicana Fiction," The Americas Review.--Vol.15, nos. 3 - 4 (1987): 171 - 188 1987 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Huerta, Jorge. "Looking for the magic: Latinos in the mainstream" n.d. (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Hughes, Dureen. "The writings of Cherríe Moraga" 1987 Feb. 16 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Jamison, Laura. Untitled draft of article 1994 May (Box 1, Folder 23)
    TMs, 4 pp.; TLS
  - Lee, Mary Hope. "Fly in a bowl of milk: Feminist writers guild workshop," Plexus (1980 Jan.): 7 1980 Jan. (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Lopez, Tiffany Ana. "Ghosts, Shadows, Heroes, and Saints: Legacy & Teatro in the drama of Cherríe Moraga" 1994 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    TMs, 21 pp.; TLS
  - MacCowan, Lyndall. Untitled essay on Cherríe Moraga n.d. (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Mendoza, Monica. "Feminist pushes for social change through theater, art," Iowa City Press Citizen (1992 Feb. 25) 1992 Feb. 25 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Olson, Sharon R. Letter to the editor re: Loving in the war years. Sonoma County Women's Voices (1984 Mar.): 2 1984 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Poniatowska, Elena. "Puentes de ida y vuelta," La Jornada Semanal (1989 June 4): 1 - 5 1989 June 4 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Rich, B. Ruby. "Introduction to Cherríe Moraga" 1991 Nov. (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Saldivar, Jose. "The rhetoric of Chicano-Chicana autobiography: a Calibanic Perspective" n.d. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Schiffman, Jean. "Talking with playwrights," Callboard.--Vol. 17, no. 7 (1992 July): 3 - 9 1992 July (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Ward, Skye. "Cherríe Moraga (1952-)," Contemporary Lesbian Writers of the United States / ed. Sandra Pollack and Denise Knight n.d. (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Warrock, Anna M. "Lesbian Poetry a new vision," Sojourner (1981 July): 25 1981 July (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Winn, Steven. "Hispanics blend into stage melting pot," San Francisco Chronicle Datebook (1989 Mar. 19): 25 - 28 1989 Mar. 19 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Yarbro-Bejarano, Yvonne. "Cherríe Moraga (25 September 1952-)," DLB.--Vol. 82 (n.d.):165 - 177 n.d. (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Yarbro-Bejarano, Yvonne. "Cherríe Moraga's Giving up the ghost: the representation of female desire" n.d. (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Yarbro-Bejarano, Yvonne. "Cherríe Moraga's Giving up the ghost and feminist theory" n.d. (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Yarbro-Bejarano, Yvonne. "Chicana literature from a Chicana Feminist Perspective," Americas Review.--Vol. 15, nos. 3 - 4 (1987) 1987 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Yarbro-Bejarano, Yvonne. "The female subject in Chicano Theatre: Sexuality, 'Race,' and Class," Theatre Journal (1986 Dec.): 389 - 407 1986 Dec. (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Yollin, Patricia. "Painting the town lavender," San Francisco Examiner (1991 Mar. 10): 18 - 29 1991 Mar. 10 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    ANS
  - [Unidentified author]. "A textual analysis of Giving up the Ghost" n.d. (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - [Unidentified author]. Article on This Bridge called my back n.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Interviews: Alarcón, Norma. "Interview with Cherríe Moraga," Third Woman.--Vol. 3, nos. 1 - 2 (1986): 127 - 134 1986 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Interviews: Allison, Dorothy, et al. "Writing is the measure of my life... an interview with Cherríe Moraga," Out/Look (1989 Winter) 1989 Winter (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Interviews: Castillo, Ana. "It's a body: Ana Castillo interviews Cherríe Moraga," American Poetry Archives News.--Vol. 5, no. 2 (1988 Fall) 1988 Fall (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Interviews: Guerrero, Lourdes & Mike Chavez. Interview with Cherríe Moraga," Chispas.--Vol. 19, nos. 2 - 3 (1991 Mar.): 8 - 10 1991 Mar. (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Interviews: Lewis, Andrea. "The Next Stage: Interview with Cherríe Moraga" [Mother Jones transcript] 1990 (Box 1, Folder 48)
    TMs, 19 pp.; TLS
  - Interviews: Poggi, Stephanie. "Family Secrets: an interview with Cherríe Moraga," Gay Community News.--Vol. 12, no. 2 (1984 July 21) 1984 July 21 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Interviews: Umpierre, Luz María. "With Cherríe Moraga," Americas Review (1986 Summer) 1986 Summer (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Interviews: Williams, Gaye. "This Bridge Called My Back: interview" 1981 Sept. 3 (Box 1, Folder 51)
    TMs, 32 pp.; ANS
  - Interviews: Wolbert, Wayne A. "Making Familia from scratch: an interview with Cherríe Moraga," Alma Latina (1995 Oct. - Nov.) 1995 Oct. -Nov. (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Interviews: [Unknown interviewer] "Interview with Cherríe Moraga" n.d. (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Reviews: Coatlicue's Call [Hurwitt, Robert. "4 Fest 2000 survivors offer mixed bag," San Francisco Examiner (1990 Oct. 26): C12] 1990 Oct. 26 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Reviews: Cuentos: Stories by Latinas [Cantu, Norma. "Cuentos: Stories by Latinas," La Red / The Net.--No. 38 (1984 Aug.): 2 - 3] 1984 Aug. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Reviews: Cuentos: Stories by Latinas [Hinojosa, María. "Stories by and about Latinas -- at last," Guardian Book Supplement (1984)] 1984 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Reviews: Cuentos: Stories by Latinas [Poggi, Stephanie. "Mujeres en Lucha," Gay Community News (1984 Apr.): 5] 1984 Apr. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Reviews: Cuentos: Stories by Latinas [Quintana, María. "Latina Rites of Passage," Belles Lettres (1985): 6 - 7] 1985 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Reviews: Cuentos: Stories by Latinas [Rebolledo, Tey Diana. "Cuentos: Stories by Latinas," El Palacio (1986): 59 - 60] 1986 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Reviews: Cuentos: Stories by Latinas [La Red / The Net.--No. 77 (1984 Feb.): 11] 1984 Feb. (Box 2, Folder 7)